

# Don Osborne UX Design & Management

Based in Los Angeles, CA 323.356.9742 don@humanfriendlydesign.com humanfriendlydesign.com

# **Background**

I'm Don Osborne, a highly experienced and award winning UX design leader with over 15 years of experience creating intuitive, user-centered designs that drive business success. I've managed designers from around the world and strive to bring out the best in my team members.

## **Experience**

## Green Dot | Principle UI Developer → UX Design Manger → Director of UX Design

Dec 2018 - Jan 2023

- Led UX team in design and launch of GO2bank mobile apps and bank account website.
- Oversaw design of all new product features such as secured credit card, overdraft protection, savings account, Experian credit boost, help center, and bill pay.
- Acted as lead designer for white label partner products launching in 2023.
- Creator and maintainer of all design systems used across Green Dot apps and websites.
- Managed a team of UX designers in the US and Shanghai, making user research and accessibility a key focus of the design group.

#### Tenable | Senior UX Designer

Sept 2017 - Dec 2018

- Designed UX/UI for Tenable's next generation network security vulnerability management in Tenable.io.
- Designed UX/UI for Lumin, a breakthrough cyber exposure visualization product.
- Designed widgets and dashboards with rich visualizations for use across Tenable's suite of products.
- Contributed to Hive Design System as part of complete product portfolio redesign.

#### Green Dot | Senior UX Designer → UX Design Manager

May 2015 - Sept 2017

- Designed & developed the Flex Web Design System, a front-end web framework for all Green Dot brands, seen on greendot.com, gobank.com, moneypak.com, greendotmoney.com, attheregister.com, simplypaid.com.
- Managed concept pitches for Apple Pay Cash, which Green Dot ultimately won the services for.
- Contributed to redesign of all Green Dot brand apps for Web, iOS and Android.

## Rovi | Web UI Designer → Senior User Interface Engineer

Nov 2012 - May 2015

- Designed & developed RoviGuide, a TV set top box prototype (winner of Multichannel News Innovator Award),
   Tilden, a HTML based European TV guide, and TotalTV, a HTML based web app built for embedding into cable and media sites.
- Utilized responsive design methodology for all products, optimizing for Mobile/Tablet/Desktop/TV sizes.

## Fidelis Education | User Experience Designer

Nov 2011 - Nov 2012

- Designed FidelisEducation.com sign up/sign in, student home page, student profile, messaging system, notifications system, activity stream, account settings, job placement search panel and course work application.
- Translated mockups to working prototypes using HTML/CSS/Javascript.

# CitizenGlobal | Product Manager & User Interface Designer

Apr 2010 - Nov 2011

- Designed UX & UI for admin panel, media manager, video uploader, desktop video uploader, user accounts, online video editor, WikiCG iOS App, WikiCG Android App and Facebook app.
- Productized requests from Management, Services and Support through user stories, wireframes and mockups.
- Managed developers in an Agile environment.

# Engine Room | Visual Effects Editor, Web Designer & Developer

Sept 2007 - Apr 2010

- Digitized, organized and output all footage entering and leaving facility.
- Managed VFX shots in Shotgun and assigned shots to artists.
- Designed & developed engineroomhollywood.com and enginedesign.tv, creating compression workflows for web video archive system.
- Implemented HTML5 video playback and Wordpress as a news publishing system.
- Designed/developed radarhollywood.com, incorporating user registration, user profile management, and admin search panel.

# 310 Casting Studios | Tech Manager, Video Editor, Web Designer & Developer

May 2006 - Sept 2007

- Designed & developed 310castingstudios.com.
- Administered live video uploads for casting sessions.
- Trained and managed camera operators on cameras, computers, editing software and web video uploads.

# In Sync Advertising | Assistant Editor, Web Designer and Systems Administrator

Feb 2005 - May 2006

- Designed and developed client video review web site.
- Digitized, organized and output all footage entering and leaving facility.
- Created video compression workflows for web and DVD.
- Managed all facility editing hardware/software, designed new HD Final Cut Pro based editing systems.

# Education

# Full Sail University

Orlando, FL

Associate of Science in Film and Video Production

# University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Charlotte, NC

Graphic Design and Multimedia

Skills